Md. Surat-E-Mostafa

Email:surat153@gmail.com

Profile

Almost 3 years experience in algorithm development in biomedical engineering, telecommunications Engineering and IOT. Data Simulation/Analysis, Physiological Signal processing(ECG, EEG), Machine learning, Artificial intelligence, test automation and test tools are the strongest expertise area. Familiar with different tasks: electrical circuit design, development, automation, HW and simulation testing.

Technical Skills

Windows

Programming languages	Skill level	Experience (Last used)
Python	Excellent	2 years
MATLAB	Excellent	4 years
C #	Good	6 months
C++	Basics	6 months
C	Basics	8 months
Javascript	Basics	6 months
R	Basics	6 months
Frameworks		
RF circuits	Basics	6 months
Digital circuits	Good	6 months
HW (Electronic)	Good	2 years
RF measur. tools	Good	6 months
ASP.NET	Good	6 months
Postman	Good	6 months
WebAPI/Rest API	Good	6 months
SQL	Good	6 months
PostgreSQL	Good	6 months
Unit testing	Good	6 months
Robot	Good	6 months
Git/GitHub	Good	1 year
Pytorch/ Tensor Flow	Good	1 year
Operating systems		
Linux	Good	2 years

Skill level is estimated with four levels: Basics - Intermediate - Good - Excellent

Good

15 years

Work Experience

Buutti Oy, Trainee, BuutCamp Agile C# Program

07 / 2020 - 01 / 2020

I worked as a trainee in BuutCamp Agile C# Program at Buutti Oy. Program was comprised of 40 days of structured learning, 4 days of career development and 76 days of practical training. During the training following topics were covered: C# basics, ASP.NET software development basics, REST architecture, And SQL databases.

University of Oulu, Research Assistant

09 / 2017 - 01 / 2019

I worked as a research assistant at the University of Oulu under a physiological signal analysis group where I was responsible for the analysis of raw data (ECG, EEG data) using Matlab and Python programming . Based on this project work, I have continued my thesis work. My thesis topic is 'Estimating Spectral HRV Features with Missing Data'.

University of Oulu, Summer trainee

06 / 2017 - 08 / 2017

During the internship period, I did work in Pain fingerprint using a multimodal sensing project. The objective of this project was to develop new technology using Matlab tools, which enables online monitoring of pain experience by observing heart rate variability.

edotcogroup, Telecommunication Engineer

02 / 2015 - 06 / 2016

The main responsibility was to look and monitor the working of the other people involved in the project and made the report for circulating the team leader. The project work related to the regional tower operation center(RTOC).

Islami Bank Institute of Technology, Lecturer

02 / 2013 - 01 / 2015

The main roles and responsibilities were:

- -Preparing and delivering regular lectures for students.
- -Conducting tutorial sessions, seminars and laboratory classes.
- -Preparing and marking student assignments, essays, exams and providing feedback on academic performance where necessary.

Ahsanullah University, Thesis Worker

01/2012 - 12/2012

My BSc thesis was on this topic of 'Ultra-high bit rate quasi-linear optical transmission system. This thesis investigates the performance of the high capacity quasi-linear optical fiber with periodic dispersion compensation by numerical simulation based on the Split Step Fourier transformation method. Two different models are considered in this thesis which are as follows, Single-Mode Fiber-Dispersion Compensating Fiber and Pre-Compensated SMF- DCF. Comparisons of Quality Factor over the Transmission Length, Transmission Power, Bit Rate and Residual Dispersion between these two models are obtained.

Projects

GitHub profile: https://github.com/polasha

Linkedin profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-surat-e-mostafa-b9184784/

GitLab profile: https://gitlab.com/SURATMOSTAFA

Education

University of Oulu: Biomedical Engineering	01 / 2019
Master of Science in Biomedical Engineering.	
Jahangirnagar University: Information and Technology	06 / 2016
Master of Engineering in Information Technology	
Ahsanullah University: Electrical Engineering	01 / 2013
Bachelor of Electrical and Electronic Engineering.	

Courses

C-sharp Basics for Beginners, Udemy	08 / 2020
Neural Networks and Deep Learning, coursera	06 / 2019
Pytorch for deep learning with python Bootcamp, Udemy	10 / 2019
Structuring Machine Learning Projects, coursera	12 / 2019
The Complete Machine Learning Course with python, Udemy	11 / 2019

Language skills

Bengali Mother tongue
English Excellent
Finnish Basics

References

Tapio Seppänen
Position : Professor

Employer: Physiological Signal Analysis team,

University of Oulu, Finland Email: tapio.seppanen@oulu.fi

Antti Isosalo

Position: Research Scientist

Employer: Physiological Signal Analysis team,

University of Oulu, Finland Email: Antti.Isosalo@oulu.fi